American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to George Ord, October 4, 1844; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Librarian of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Ord to extend the facilities of the A.P.S. library to Mr. McCulloh.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, Oct. 10, 1844; 10x7-1/2; Moore, George Henry, 1823-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Encloses publications of the Historical society of New York and asks for missing numbers of APS publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 12, 1844; 6" x 7 3/4"; Mitchell, John Kearsley, 1793-1858
    1 p., address and endorsement. 3d. per. N.S. Requests loan or specified issues of The Journals of Congress.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 14, 1844; 4 15/16" x 7 7/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Sends first six volumes of Transactions [of A.P.S.] for the Royal Society of Lille.
  - Report of committee on paper by [John' Locke on "Magnetic observations", Oct. 15, 1844; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: John F. Frazer, A. D. Bache, and Charles McEuen. 1p.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, October 15, 1844; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Sartori, John B.
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Leghorn, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning settlement of accounts with the American Philosophical Society.
  - Statement of account with the American philosophical society, Oct. 15, 1844; 10-1/2x8; Sartori, John B.
    Leghorn, A.D.S. 1p.,end.,and end.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 16, 1844; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether Professor Bache wishes two copies of A.P.S. Transactions, II.
  - Letter to ----, October 17, 1844; 8 1/4" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Hall of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. Pr.D.S.: John K. Kane, George Ord, R[obert] M. Patterson. Invitation to attend discourse in commemoration of Peter S. DuPonceau, on October 25th.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, October 17, 1844; 7 3/8" x 7 3/4"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. Mr. Curtis, of North Carolina, who wishes to use [G. H. E.] Muhlenberg's herbarium. MOSES ASHLEY CURTIS
  - Letter to George Ord, October 21, 1844; 5" x 7 7/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Sends volumes 1, 5, 6, 7 and 8 (A.P.S. Transactions) for the use of the library.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, George Ord, and R.M. Patterson, October 22, 1844; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Johnson, Walter R. (Walter Rogers), 1794-1852
    [Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Academy of Natural Sciences accepts invitation to be present upon delivery of address in commemoration of Peter S. DuPonceau.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, George Ord, and R.M. Patterson, October 23, 1844; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jackson, William
    Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Pennsylvania State Society of the Cincinnati accepts invitation to be present at discourse in commemoration of Peter S. DuPonceau.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, George Ord, and R.M. Patterson, October 25, 1844; 8" x 10"; Brewster, F. Carroll (Frederick Carroll), 1825-1898
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Law Academy accepts invitation to attend discourse in commemoration of Peter S. DuPonceau.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, October 25, 1844; 6 3/16" x 7 3/4"; Dillingham, William H., 1791-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that an invitation to Dr. [Robley] Dunglison's discourse be given to Dr. Solomon D. Townsend of Boston.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 28, 1844; 10x8; New-York Historical Society
    New York, Printed L. filled in and S: Eras. C. Benedict, Secretary, 1p. and end. Invitation to attend anniversary celebration, Nov. 20, 1844. See APS Minutes [Ms] Nov. 15, 1844, p.250.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, October 29, 1844; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Bossange, Edouard
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of 24th., together with box of periodicals for the Society of Lille.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct., 1844; 10x7-1/2; New-York Historical Society
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S: George Gibbs. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings. On same sheet in letter from G.H.Moore to G.Ord; Oct.10, 1844.
  - Report of committee on arrangements regarding discourse in commemoration of the late President, Nov. 1, 1844; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    DuPonceau; [Philadelphia] D.S.: J.K.Kane, G.Ord, and R.M.Patterson. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 109-110.
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], November 1, 1844; 7 13/16" x 9 5/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsements. Pr.D. Sends to the A.P.S.: a map of New York bay and harbor.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 2, 1844; 9x7; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Clarke. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, November 6, 1844; 5" x 7 7/8"; Benedict, Erastus Cornelius, 1800-1880
    New York, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Ord to address and deliver enclosed invitations to presidents of A.P.S. and Historical Society [of Pennsylvania], whose names he does not know.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 7, 1844; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S: William J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: P.Vaughan. Esq. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, November 7, 1844; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends by Susquehanna: four numbers of Altona journals and Transactions of the Zoological Society [of London].
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 8, 1844; 10x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
  - Letter to the [American] Philosophical Society, November 9, 1844; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Zantedeschi, Francesco, 1797-1873
    Venice, 2 pp. and endorsement, A.L.S. (In Italian.) --- 2 pp. English translation. Presents to the A.P.S.: the first part of his treatise on magnetism and electricity. Printed in part: APS Proceedings,V.90, no.5,December, 1946.
  - Report of committee on paper by Major Graham, Nov. 12, 1844; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Sears C. Walker and R.M. Patterson. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 111-112.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., November 13, 1844; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; King, Richard, 1811?-1876
    [London], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Ethnological Society of London, Journal, I, i, ii; II, i.
  - Letter to the President of the [American] Philosophical Society, November 13, 1844; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Thornton, Anna Maria Brodeau, 1775?-1865
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a work on volcanoes.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, November 14, 1844; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hollinshead, Benjamin M.
    No. 14 N. 6th St., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Desires to show two ladies the curiosities in the hall of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 14, 1844; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Flourens. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Report of committee on paper by [Elias] Loomis, Nov. 18, 1844; 7-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Sears C. Walker, R. M. Patterson, and E. Otis Kendall. 1p. and end. See APS Proceedings, IV, 112.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 18, 1844; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of order for £13.2.9. Bequest of [Nathan] Dunn. [Charles] Waterton sends copy of his last work, to go by the next packet.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 22, 1844; 9-3/4x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich[olas] Carlisle. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, November 26, 1844; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Nulty, Eugenius
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether the A.P.S. would be interested in publishing his work on the magic cyclovolute. See Pro., IV, 125.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 29, 1844; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Society of Antiquaries of London
    [London], 1p. and endorsement. L.S.: Nich[hola]s Carlisle. Forwards to the A.P.S.: Archaeologia, XXX, and index to vols. XVI-XXX.
  - Letter to the Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., November, 1844; 7 13/16" x 11 11/16"; Leavitt, Dudley, 1830-1908
    Meredith, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends "Tables" to the A.P.S. for calculating the moon Laplace
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 1, 1844; 6" x 8 5/16"; Irwin, William W.
    U.S. Legation, Copenhagen, 1p. and endorsements. L.S. U.S. minister transmits a donation from [N.C.L.] Abrahams, cited herein, to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 7, 1844; 7 1/2" x 9"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    Treasurer of A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends per T. P. Cope: Altona journals; British Almanac for 1845; packet from the Linnean Society [of London].
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, December 7, 1844; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Treasurer of A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Forwards a parcel from the Statistical Society and one from the Leeds Philosophical and Literary Society to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, Philadelphia, Dec. 9, 1844; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Walter R. Johnson. 1p. ,end.and add. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, December 10, 1844; 8 3/4" x 10 7/8"; McCulloh, R. S. (Richard Sears), 1818-1894
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1p,. address and endorsement Wishes to use designated issues of the Comptes rendus de l'Academie, and will call for the same at the library of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Isaac Lea, Philadelphia, Dec. 10, 1844; 10x7-1/2; New-York Historical Society
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: George Gibbs. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, December 11, 1844; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Nulty, Eugenius
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Advises against the publication of [John] Ewing's magic square.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 13, 1844; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Reale accademia delle scienze di Torino
    Turin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Gené 1p.,end.: A.L.E[lwyn] and add. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Report of committee on paper by Dr. Bond on "Spina bifida", Dec. 19, 1844; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Ch. D. Meigs and Robley Dunglison. 1p. end. See APS Proceedings, IV, 124-125.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, December 19, 1844; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Bartlett, W. H. C. (William Holms Chambers), 1804-1893
    Secretary of A.P.S., West Point, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Accepts membership on committee to collect observations on solar eclipse of the 9th instant. See Pro., IV, 134.
  - Report of committee on paper by [E. Nulty] on the "Different forms of the magic cyclovolute", Dec. 20, 1844; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R. M. Patterson and Ellwood Morris. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 125-126. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., X, 17-25.
  - Letter to Jos[eph] Henry, December 20, 1844; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Maxwell, John Patterson Bryan, 1804-1845
    Princeton, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding the dentition of the mastodon. See Pro., IV, 126-127.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 27, 1844; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Librarian of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. Does not expect to be in Philadelphia on January 3. Extends New Year greetings to Mr. Ord. FILM 235 FRAME 33